<metadata xml:lang="fi"><Esri><CreaDate>20160922</CreaDate><CreaTime>11292600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20161104</ModDate><ModTime>15170400</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><tool name="CalculateWeightsTool" displayname="Calculate Weights" toolboxalias="ArcSDM" xmlns=""><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.4\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><parameters><param name="evidence_raster_layer" displayname="Evidence Raster Layer" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Raster Layer" expression="evidence_raster_layer"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Evidence raster layer that defines the patterns and pattern values that the training points are intersected with. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Only integer rasters can be used for evidence. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Evidence_Raster_Code_Field" displayname="Evidence raster codefield" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Field" expression="{Evidence_Raster_Code_Field}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Free or categorical evidence layer field containing description of Value field. This attribute is not used in Cumulative weights analysis. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Training_points" displayname="Training points" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Layer" expression="Training_points"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Training Points used to calculate the weights and associated statistics. Training points "train" the model. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Type" displayname="Type" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="Descending | Ascending | Categorical | Unique"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Type of weights table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ascending by pattern areas for an ordered evidence layer. Use this measure when a low threshold is desired, such as for a distance raster to answer the question of near to or proximal to something. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Descending by pattern areas for an ordered evidence layer. Use this measure when a high threshold is desired, such as for a distance raster to answer the question of far from something. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Categorical for a categorical or free evidence layer. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Unique for an ungeneralized evidence layer. This is useful for Expert or Fuzzy WofE and Logistic Regression ungeneralized ordered data. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="output_weights_table" displayname="Output weights table" type="Required" direction="Output" datatype="Table" expression="output_weights_table"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Required pathname or filename for weights table containing W+, W-, their standard deviations, Contrast, and Studentized Contrast, generalized Cass, Weight, and its standard deviations. For example, kbgeol2_CT.dbf. Note the ".dbf" extension is required.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;'_CA' for Cumulative Ascending Weights &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;'_CD' for Cumulative Descending weights &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;'_CT' for Categorical weights &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;'_U' for Ungeneralized Weights. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If the named table exists and has the Weights of Evidence format, its rows will be deleted and rewritten.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Confidence_Level_of_Studentized_Contrast" displayname="Confidence Level of Studentized Contrast" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Double" expression="Confidence_Level_of_Studentized_Contrast"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This measure defines an acceptable Contrast. This measure is an approximate Student T test of the hypothesis that the contrast is not zero. Default level is 2.0, which is approximately 98% confidence. The user should select a confidence level appropriate to the problem. The default may not be appropriate to the user's problem.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For ordered data by Ascending or Descending weights of evidence, the evidence is generalized into binary classes, 1 and 2. The break point between class 1 and 2 is defined as the maximum contrast that has a Confidence Level of Studentized Contrast greater than or equal to the user defined Confidence Level of Studentized Contrast. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generalized class value = 2 is assigned to classes that meet this confidence criteria. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Generalized class value = 1 is assigned to classes that do not meet this confidence criteria. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For Free (Categorical) data, any class that has an absolute value of the Confidence Level of the Studentized Contrast greater than or equal to the user defined confidence is accepted. All other classes are grouped together as one class. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Acceptable classes are given a Gen Class value equal to the value in the evidence. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Classes that do not meet the confidence critieria are grouped together with a Gen Class value of 99 or some value that does not equal one of the evidence class values. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Unit_Area__sq_km_" displayname="Unit area (km2)" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Double" expression="Unit_Area__sq_km_"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Unit Area is used as the counting unit for area measurements in Weights of Evidence and Logistic Regression. Thus area is measured not as true area, but as counts of unit cells. In the Reponse theme, the posterior probability will be the probability of a Unit Cell containing a training point.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Unit Area should be a small area relative to the total study area. This area is used as the area of a single training point. The software has a limit for the posterior probability of 0.000001. If the resulting probabilities for a model are smaller than this limit, increasing the unit area will increase the posterior probability.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is essential that the selected Unit Cell is a small number relative to the total area. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use the Training Sites Reduction tool to select a subset of training sites or to eliminate multiple training sites in a unit cell. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Unit Area must be no smaller than the cell size. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Missing_Data_Value" displayname="Missing data value" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Long" expression="Missing_Data_Value"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Value where evidence is missing in study area. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This Missing Data area in an evidence layer must be explicitly reclassified as the Missing Data value in the evidence layer. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Areas of NoData will be ignored from the calculations and the response themes. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param></parameters><summary>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use this tool to calculate weights for a single integer evidential grid and generalize the theme based on the weights statistics. THE ENVIRONMENT MUST BE SET BEFORE RUNNING THIS AND ALL SUBSEQUENT TOOLS. THE EVIDENCE MUST BE CLIPPED TO THE STUDY AREA BEFORE USING THIS SUBSEQUENT WofE TOOLS. See tips in Help for details. A set of statistics, including the area, number of training points, W+, W-, Contrast and their standard deviations, as well as the Studentized Contrast are calculated for each class in the specified class field and written to a DBF file. For Ordered data (ordinal, interval, and ratio scales), these statistics can be calculated cumulatively from lowest to highest class (ascending) or highest to lowest class (descending). Free data (categorical scale) can be only calculated for the classes, The resulting tables can be reviewed to evaluate if the statistics and generalization results are acceptable. If not acceptable, then the integer evidence can be reclassified using the Reclassify tool and the weights calculated on the reclassified integer evidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</summary></tool><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Calculate Weights</resTitle></idCitation><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use this tool to calculate weights for a single integer evidential grid and generalize the theme based on the weights statistics. THE ENVIRONMENT MUST BE SET BEFORE RUNNING THIS AND ALL SUBSEQUENT TOOLS. THE EVIDENCE MUST BE CLIPPED TO THE STUDY AREA BEFORE USING THIS SUBSEQUENT WofE TOOLS. See tips in Help for details. A set of statistics, including the area, number of training points, W+, W-, Contrast and their standard deviations, as well as the Studentized Contrast are calculated for each class in the specified class field and written to a DBF file. For Ordered data (ordinal, interval, and ratio scales), these statistics can be calculated cumulatively from lowest to highest class (ascending) or highest to lowest class (descending). Free data (categorical scale) can be only calculated for the classes, The resulting tables can be reviewed to evaluate if the statistics and generalization results are acceptable. If not acceptable, then the integer evidence can be reclassified using the Reclassify tool and the weights calculated on the reclassified integer evidence.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Tool</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv></metadata>
