<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="fi"><Esri><CreaDate>20200513</CreaDate><CreaTime>15133600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20200515</ModDate><ModTime>10184600</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange></Esri><tool name="FuzzyROC2" displayname="Fuzzy ROC 2" toolboxalias="ArcSDM" xmlns=""><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><parameters><param name="inputrasters" displayname="Input rasters, Fuzzy Membership functions and parameters" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Value Table" expression="Input raster name {Membership type} {Midpoint Min} {Midpoint Max} {Midpoint Count} {Spread Min} {Spread Max} {Spread Count};Input raster name {Membership type} {Midpoint Min} {Midpoint Max} {Midpoint Count} {Spread Min} {Spread Max} {Spread Count}..."><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At least two Input Raster names, Membership functions and parameters for each Input raster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Membership function description:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Gaussian — Assigns a membership value of 1 at the midpoint.The membership decreases to 0 for values that deviate from the midpoint according to a normal curve. Gaussian is similar to the Near function but has a more narrow spread. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Small — Used to indicate that small values of the input raster have high membership in the fuzzy set. Assigns a membership value of 0.5 at the midpoint. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Large — Used to indicate that large values of the input raster have high membership in the fuzzy set. Assigns a membership value of 0.5 at the midpoint. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Near — Calculates memberships for values near some intermediate value. Assigns a membership value of 1 at the midpoint. The membership decreases to 0 for values that deviate from the midpoint. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• MSLarge — Calculates membership based on the mean and standard deviation of the input data where large values have high membership. The result can be similar to the Large function, depending on how the multipliers of the mean and standard deviation are defined. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• MSSmall — Calculates membership based on the mean and standard deviation of the input data where small values have high membership. This is the default membership type. The result can be similar to the Small function, depending on how the multipliers of the mean and standard deviation are defined. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Linear — Calculates membership based on the linear transformation of the input raster. Assigns a membership value of 0 at the minimum and a membership of 1 at the maximum. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="foparams" displayname="Fuzzy Overlay Parameters" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Value Table" expression="Overlay type {Parameter};Overlay type {Parameter}..."><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Fuzzy Overlay parameter is selected from the drop-down menu. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Overlay type specifies the method used to combine two or more membership data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• And — The minimum of the fuzzy memberships from the input fuzzy rasters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Or — The maximum of the fuzzy memberships from the input rasters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Product — A decreasive function. Use this when the combination of multiple evidence is less important or smaller than any of the inputs alone.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Sum — An increasive function. Use this when the combination of multiple evidence is more important or larger than any of the inputs alone.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Gamma — The algebraic product of the fuzzy Sum and fuzzy Product, both raised to the power of gamma.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Parameter: The gamma value to be used. This is only available when the Overlay type is set to GAMMA. Default value is 0.9.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="truepositives" displayname="ROC True Positives Feature Class" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Class" expression="truepositives"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Feature Class containing known positive cases.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="dest_folder" displayname="ROC Destination Folder" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Folder" expression="dest_folder"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The folder where the tool writes the results.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param></parameters><summary>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select at least 2 Input Rasters and one Fuzzy Membership function and &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;its &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;parameters to each raster. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Functions are: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gaussian, Small, Large, Near, MSLarge, MSSmall, Linear&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;You can use only one function for each raster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Parameters are: Midpoint Min (minimum value of Midpoint), Midpoint Max (maximum value of Midpoint) Midpoint Count (number of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Midpoint&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; values at regular intervals min to max&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;)&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;, Spread Min, Max and Count likewise&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tool executes Fuzzy Membership tool for each combination of Midpoint and Spread values and writes output rasters from each execution. Tool writes all output raster names to FuzzyMembership.csv table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Tool executes Fuzzy Overlay tool combining all Fuzzy Membership outputs in pairs and executes ROC tool to each Fuzzy Overlay outputs. Tool writes all  outpur raster names to FuzzyOverlay.csv table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;At last tool collects all ROC AUC values to FuzzyROC.csv table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</summary></tool><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Fuzzy ROC 2</resTitle></idCitation><searchKeys><keyword>fuzzyroc2</keyword></searchKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Tool</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20200515</mdDateSt></metadata>
