<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20171003</CreaDate><CreaTime>10221300</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20171006</ModDate><ModTime>10385900</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><tool name="GrandWofe" displayname="Grand WOFE" toolboxalias="ArcSDM" xmlns=""><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.4\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><parameters><param name="wofename" displayname="Grand WOFE name" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="wofename"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A short name for Spatial Data Modeller models' tests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Each model test is tagged with character beginning with 'A'.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Example: GW1&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="rasternames" displayname="Input raster names" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Multiple Value" expression="rasternames;rasternames..."><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;One or more input evidence rasters.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="rastertypes" displayname="Input raster types" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="rastertypes"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Add one evidence type (ordered or free or categorical or ascending or descending) for each evidence raster in order. Free and Categorical can be used interchangeably. Ascending or descending as appropriate. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ascending is entered as a or A, descending as d or D. Ordered can be entered as an O or o.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Categorical can be entered more simply as f, F, C, or c.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Training_points" displayname="Training points" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Layer" expression="Training_points"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;T&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;raining Points shapefile used to calculate the weights and associated statistics. Training points "train" the model&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Ignore missing data" displayname="Ignore missing data" type="Optional" direction="Output" datatype="Boolean" expression="{Ignore missing data}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Ignore missing data in calculations: checked (True) or unchecked&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Not checked is the default.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Missing data value in evidence is -99. The evidence raster must have a -99 value designating areas of Missing Data, if Missning Data are to be dealt with.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="contrast" displayname="Contrast Confidence Level" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Double" expression="contrast"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Confidence Contrast lowest acceptable level.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Default is 2.0, an approximate confidence of 98% that the observed value differs from zero.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="Unit_Area__sq_km_" displayname="Unit area (km2)" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Double" expression="Unit_Area__sq_km_"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Area of unit cell in square kilometers.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param></parameters><summary>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To use this tool well requires a basic understanding of the WofE and LR methods and assumptions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Grand WofE does complete Weights of Evidence (WofE) and Logistic Regression (LR) models. This includes the calculation of weights and generalization of the evidence and then the calculation of the WofE and LR response rasters on every combination of valid weights tables for one or more evidence layers. Thus, this tool combines the functions of Calculate Weights and Calculate Response into one tool&amp;lt;/P&amp;gt;&amp;lt;P&amp;gt;Weights tables are created and can be inspected to understand the models. See the Help files for Calculate Weights for a complete explanation of these tables.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See the Help files for Calculate Response and Logistic Regression for documentation on the files created.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;THE ENVIRONMENT MUST BE SET BEFORE RUNNING THIS AND ALL SUBSEQUENT TOOLS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. See tips in Help of Calculate Weights for details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</summary><usage>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;While Grand WofE is calculating the Ordered weights tables, the following messages will appear:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Valid Wts Table - This indicate that the Cumulative Descending or Cumulative Ascending (CA) weights satisfied the user specified confidence criteria.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Invalid Wts Table - This indicate that the Cumulative Descending or Cumulative Ascending (CA) weights did not satisfy the user specified confidence criteria.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Cases have occurred where a single evidence will yield a valid weights table for both Cumulative Ascending (CA) and Cumulative Descending (CD) methods. An example might be proximity to a river and people don't want to live too close because of the danger of flooding, but they don't want to live too far away from the river because it is too far to bring water. So people like to live near rivers but not too close to rivers, that is some distance in the middle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Such evidence is better dealt with by inspection of the weights tables to define the overlapping intervals in the middle and then the evidence is reclassified to have a class in the middle and two intervals for the outside class. The Reclassify (sa) tool does this reclassification well. Calculate Weights using the Categorical method is often a useful way to define such intervals in the middle.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If a valid weights table is found by both CA and CD methods, then multiple models will be created using each of these weights tables with the evidence. The better model is normally the one using the weighting method that is applicable to the process being modeled. Thus the user must have some understanding of the process being modeled to select the appropriate evidence for a model and best modeled response.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A similar Valid/Invalid message will appear for Categorical evidence. A Categorical evidence will only be used in the models if it has a Valid weights table. In the case of an Invalid weights table, inspection of the weights table may give some insights into how to reclassify the evidence to gain a Valid weights table.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P STYLE="margin:1 1 1 20;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Grand WofE will create a WofE and LR model. Typically the WofE model will have some degree of conditional dependency, which causes the reported posterior probabilities to be inflated. Use the Agterberg-Cheng tool to test for conditional dependencies in the WofE model.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P STYLE="margin:1 1 1 20;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are several tests that should be done to validate the models produced. The Area Frequency tool can be used to test the efficiency of classification of the training points. With points not used in the model the Area Frequency tool can test the efficiency of prediction. See the Help file of the Area Frequency tool for documentation on these validation tests.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P STYLE="margin:1 1 1 20;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These efficiency tests are useful validation tests that can be applied in the laboratory. The ultimate test is to test the predictions of the models in the field&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</usage></tool><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Grand WOFE</resTitle></idCitation><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;To use this tool well requires a basic understanding of the WofE and LR methods and assumptions.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Grand WofE does complete Weights of Evidence (WofE) and Logistic Regression (LR) models. This includes the calculation of weights and generalization of the evidence and then the calculation of the WofE and LR response rasters on every combination of valid weights tables for one or more evidence layers. Thus, this tool combines the functions of Calculate Weights and Calculate Response into one tool&amp;lt;/P&amp;gt;&amp;lt;P&amp;gt;Weights tables are created and can be inspected to understand the models. See the Help files for Calculate Weights for a complete explanation of these tables.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See the Help files for Calculate Response and Logistic Regression for documentation on the files created.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;THE ENVIRONMENT MUST BE SET BEFORE RUNNING THIS AND ALL SUBSEQUENT TOOLS&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. See tips in Help of Calculate Weights for details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><searchKeys><keyword>Grand Weights of Evidence</keyword><keyword>Calculate Weights Tables</keyword><keyword>Calculate Response</keyword><keyword>Logistic Regression</keyword></searchKeys><idCredit>Converted by Tero Rönkkö. Original credits to their respective copyright owners.</idCredit></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Tool</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv></metadata>
