<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20170714</CreaDate><CreaTime>10234800</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20170718</ModDate><ModTime>13222700</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><tool name="NeuralNetworkInputFiles" displayname="Neural network input files" toolboxalias="ArcSDM" xmlns=""><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.4\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><parameters><param name="inputraster" displayname="Input Unique Conditions raster" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Raster Layer" expression="inputraster"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;•	Unique Conditions raster from Combine. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;•	SDMUC raster from ArcSDM will not work because its evidence names have aliased names.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="training_sites" displayname="Training sites" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Layer" expression="training_sites"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Training sites feature layer.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="fzmfield" displayname="TP FZM Field" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Field" expression="fzmfield"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;•	Don't use deposits fuzzy membership if left blank. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;•	Otherwise, select fuzzy membership field of training sites feature layer.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="ndtraining_sites" displayname="ND Training sites" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Layer" expression="ndtraining_sites"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Non-deposits training sites feature layer.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;These sites are examples of what is not being modeled. For example in a pollution study, these might be unpolluted sites where polluted sites are usef for Training Sites.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="ndfzmfield" displayname="ND TP FZM Field" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Field" expression="ndfzmfield"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Don't use non-deposits fuzzy membership if left blank.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Otherwise, select fuzzy membership field of non-deposits training sites feature layer.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="trainingfileprefix" displayname="Training file prefix" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="trainingfileprefix"/><param name="classificationfile" displayname="Classification file" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{classificationfile}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When checked classification file is created.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Defaults to Unique Conditions raster name with '_class.dta' suffix or to prefix of given training file name and suffix.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="bandstatisticsfile" displayname="Band statistics file" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="File" expression="bandstatisticsfile"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Optional path name of band statistics file.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If left blank, the band statistics are retrieved from the evidence layers of the Unique Conditions raster.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="trainfileoutput" displayname="Train file output" type="Required" direction="Output" datatype="File" expression="trainfileoutput"/><param name="classfileoutput" displayname="Class file output" type="Required" direction="Output" datatype="File" expression="classfileoutput"/></parameters><summary>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use this tool to create the input ASCII files for the GeoXplore neural network. Before using this tool, the evidence must be combined into a unique conditions raster with the Combine tool and the band statistics must be obtained for all the evidence using the Band Collection Statistics tool. If desired a fuzzy membership attribute can be added to each of the training sites.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See the ArcMap Tools Options discussion in Usage Tips in the Help about adjusting default setting for this tool.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The sequence of tools for the neural nets is as follows:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Run Combine and Band Collection Statistics to create the combined evidence raster and a text file of the statistics of the evidence. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Neural Net Input Files - to create the input files for GeoXplore.exe. These files will have the names #_Train.dta and #_Class.dta, where # is the name of the combined evidence raster. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• GeoXplore - to run GeoXplore.exe &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Neural Net Output Files - to read the output files from GeoXplore.exe and convert them to a single DBF file that can be joined to the Combined evdience raster to map the response.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</summary><usage>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Environment Settings&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The environment must be set before this tool is run. The following parameters must be set:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Workspace - a folder where tables and calculated rasters are kept. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Scratch Workspace - a folder for various temporary tables, files, and rasters are stored. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Extent - use the raster defining the area to be studied, the study area. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Cell Size Mask - defining the study area to be modeled. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The environment for an MXD can be set by right clicking on the ArcToolbox icon and selecting Environment from the drop-down window. Set this way, this environment applies to all ArcToolbox tools and is remembered between sessions in the MXD. These Environment settings are independent of the Options settings in the Spatial Analyst.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Usage&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Fuzzy memberships of the training sites can be used to weight the importance of the training sites. Thus this provides a mechanism to differentiate big and small training sites in a model of big sites, but still use the small sites. This fuzzy membership is utilized in the RBFLN and PNN supervised neural networks. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The supervised neural networks, RBFLN and PNN, both use the training sites. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The Fuzzy Neural network is unsupervised, so it does not use the training sites in the same sense as the supervised neural nets. The training sites for the Fuzzy Neural Network can be thought of as a sample of the evidence. Thus if the same training sites are used for the supervised and unsupervised neural networks, similar results are obtained. If a same of the evidence is used, then "natural clusters" in the evidence are defined. It is then up to the user to define the meaning or significance of these "natural clusters", which is an interesting data exploration tool. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• A Random point shapefile useful as a training set for the Fuzzy Neural Net can be created using the Create Random Points tool. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;ArcMap Tool Options&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In ArcMap/Tools/Options on the Geoprocessing tab, check Overwrite the outputs of Geoprocessing operations. This will allow the user to overwrite previous files. You will see a warning in the tool window if the process is going to overwrite. This is especially useful if you want to experiment with the model.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;In ArcMap/Tools/Options on the Raster tab on the Raster Attribute Table subtab, the default raster table size is set to 65.536. This limits the largest table from the combination of evidence made with combine to 65,536 records. Often with complex sets of evidence for neural nets, which are combined using the Combine tool, the resulting combined-evidence or unique conditions raster will have a larger number of combinations of the evidence. It is essential that the combined-evidence raster table is complete for this tool to work. Therefore, increase the maximum number of records appropriately. We have successfully done combinations slightly larger than 2,000,000 records. This, of course, requires a computer with a fast processor and lots of memory.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Alternate Approaches&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are several different approaches to using the neural networks.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The demonstration neural net model can be used as a general purpose application. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Another application occurs when there are several different sets of training points that are to be applied to the data. In this case, combination of the evidence and the band statistics only need to be created once. Also the Classificaiton File (Class.dta) only needs to be created once. A different Training File (Train.dta) would then be created for each different training set that is to be applied to the same classification data. Then the final map areas might be defined by the areas that have the largest membership in each training set. Such a classificaiton from several rastes can be done with the conditional tool, Con. This approach has been used to make mineral maps from ASTER data and surficial geologic maps from geophysical data. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• There is also the consideration of which neural net funcition is appropriate for a particular application. Some considerations are the following: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The RBFLN is slower than the PNN, but the RBFLN seems to be a better classifier, at least for the applications we have tested. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The RBFNL is sensitive to the "Not" training sites. The PNN is not sensitive to the "Not" training sites. Depending on the question being addressed by the model, one of these methods may be more appropriate. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The assignment of fuzzy membership values to both types of training sites can improve the classification. This might allow for differentiation of big sites from little sites. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The Fuzzy Neural Net is an unsupervised method. Thus the training sites are a sample of the evidence. The use of this method with training sites for the RBFLN or PNN seems to give results similar to the RBFLN and PNN methods. When a sample of the evidence are used for training, the same result as the RBFLN or PNN can be found, but also other possibly interesting clusters will often be found. This is a useful approach to data exploration. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• The PNN seems to have a problem with the distribution of the membership values. They seem to all bunch together at the high end, near 1. So the quantile symbolization method seems to work best. Consequently, the values do not seem to be good membership values. These membership values should probably be reclassified if they are to be used as input into another model. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Typically with a given training set, similar resutls can be obtained with any of the three neural nets. Also, in our experience, generally the same results as the neural nets can be obtained with WofE, LR, or Fuzzy Logic. The differences between these various methods seem more related to the available evidence, the available training sites, and how the evidence is preprocessed for use in the models. Some results using raw ASTER data to make mineralogical maps might only be possible with the neural nets because of the capability for nonlinear classification. More needs to be learned about this potential applilcation.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Class.dta limited to 200,000 records&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Because of the 200,000 record limitation to GeoXplore, it is sometimes necessary to take other approaches when the evidence produces more than 200,000 unique condtions. Several approaches might be considered.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Increase the cell size. Many times by increasing the cell size, the number of unique conditions will decrease. Use the nearest neighbor method for decreasing the cell size in order to not distort the values. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Reclassify the evidence. Many different appraoches to reclassification can be used to decrease the number of values in an evidence raster. These include the following: &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Reclassify the evidence. Many different approaches to reclassification can be used to decrease the number of values in an evidence raster. These include the following:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Rescale the evidence by division by 10, 100, etc. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Reclassify the evidence using the reclassify tool. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Another type of reclassification might be to assign fuzzy membership values. Then convert these fuzzy memberships to integer values. This approach allows keeping value differences in important ranges of the data. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Subdivide the total Study area into subregions. Obtain the Band Collection Statistics for all of the evidence for the total Study area. Use this Band Collection Statistics for all subsequent calculations. Then create a train.dta file with the total area or some subset of the total study area that is appropriate for training. Then create Class.dta files for subareas that provide files with less than 200,000 records. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• An alternative to subsetting the areas to create Class.dta files with less than 200,000 records would be to edit the Class.dta file for the total study area into subfiles. After classifying these subfiles with GeoXplore, the response files would be edited and combined into one grand response file. Care must be taken to have the correct record IDs in the grand response file.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Train.dta Format&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The train.dta file is used for training the neural net. The records in this file are defined by the intersection of the training points with the unique condition raster, which is made with the Combine tool. The neural net requires only one training record for an individual unique condition. All unique conditions will not have, however, training sites.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Often it occurs that more than one training site occurs in a unique condition, either multiple "Deposit" or "Not Deposit" or combinations of both sites. These multiple records need to be reduced to only one training site per unique condition. The rule of selecting the site to keep is simply keep the one with the largest fuzzy membership. If there are several with the same fuzzy membership in a unique condition, then the first one found is kept. Typically the fuzzy membership of the "Deposit" sites will be larger than the fuzzy membership of the "Not Deposit" sites.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The format of the Train.dta file is explained in the GeoXplore.pdf file accessible from this documentation. In the Train.dta file, records 5 and beyond contain the training sites and normalized evidence as explained in the GeoXplore documentation. That documentation states, however, that columns 2 and 3 in the data records are ignored by GeoXplore. Therefore, we have used these two columns to store useful information. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Column 2 contains the FID number of the training site record selected. In order to differentiate between sites from the "Deposit" and "Not Deposit" shapefiles, the FID number is recorded for "Deposit" sites and 1000 + FID number is recorded for the "Not Deposit" sites. Thus a number such as 25 is FID number 25 in the "Deposit" shapefile. A number such as 1025 or 1225 indicates FID numbers 25 or 225 in the "Not Deposit" shapefile. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Column 3 contains the value attribute number of the unique condition that is represented by the normalized evidence in the record. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When GeoXplore is run in training mode, it reports how the record number in the train.dta file was classified. By inspecting this recording in the Train.dta file, the training site point and unique condition record can be determined. This information is useful if certain training sites fail to classify properly. Inspection of such training sites can lead to a better understanding of the sites proposed for training. Sometimes such sites are inappropriate.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</usage></tool><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Neural network input files</resTitle></idCitation><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Use this tool to create the input ASCII files for the GeoXplore neural network. Before using this tool, the evidence must be combined into a unique conditions raster with the Combine tool and the band statistics must be obtained for all the evidence using the Band Collection Statistics tool. If desired a fuzzy membership attribute can be added to each of the training sites.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;See the ArcMap Tools Options discussion in Usage Tips in the Help about adjusting default setting for this tool.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The sequence of tools for the neural nets is as follows:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Run Combine and Band Collection Statistics to create the combined evidence raster and a text file of the statistics of the evidence. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Neural Net Input Files - to create the input files for GeoXplore.exe. These files will have the names #_Train.dta and #_Class.dta, where # is the name of the combined evidence raster. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• GeoXplore - to run GeoXplore.exe &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;• Neural Net Output Files - to read the output files from GeoXplore.exe and convert them to a single DBF file that can be joined to the Combined evdience raster to map the response.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Tool</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv></metadata>
